Help on module cv2.aruco in cv2:

NAME
    cv2.aruco

FUNCTIONS
    Board_create(...)
        Board_create(objPoints, dictionary, ids) -> retval
        .   * @brief Provide way to create Board by passing nessesary data. Specially needed in Python.
        .   *
        .   * @param objPoints array of object points of all the marker corners in the board
        .   * @param dictionary the dictionary of markers employed for this board
        .   * @param ids vector of the identifiers of the markers in the board
        .   *
    
    CharucoBoard_create(...)
        CharucoBoard_create(squaresX, squaresY, squareLength, markerLength, dictionary) -> retval
        .   * @brief Create a CharucoBoard object
        .   *
        .   * @param squaresX number of chessboard squares in X direction
        .   * @param squaresY number of chessboard squares in Y direction
        .   * @param squareLength chessboard square side length (normally in meters)
        .   * @param markerLength marker side length (same unit than squareLength)
        .   * @param dictionary dictionary of markers indicating the type of markers.
        .   * The first markers in the dictionary are used to fill the white chessboard squares.
        .   * @return the output CharucoBoard object
        .   *
        .   * This functions creates a CharucoBoard object given the number of squares in each direction
        .   * and the size of the markers and chessboard squares.
    
    DetectorParameters_create(...)
        DetectorParameters_create() -> retval
        .
    
    Dictionary_create(...)
        Dictionary_create(nMarkers, markerSize[, randomSeed]) -> retval
        .   * @see generateCustomDictionary
    
    Dictionary_create_from(...)
        Dictionary_create_from(nMarkers, markerSize, baseDictionary[, randomSeed]) -> retval
        .   * @see generateCustomDictionary
    
    Dictionary_get(...)
        Dictionary_get(dict) -> retval
        .   * @see getPredefinedDictionary
    
    Dictionary_getBitsFromByteList(...)
        Dictionary_getBitsFromByteList(byteList, markerSize) -> retval
        .   * @brief Transform list of bytes to matrix of bits
    
    Dictionary_getByteListFromBits(...)
        Dictionary_getByteListFromBits(bits) -> retval
        .   * @brief Transform matrix of bits to list of bytes in the 4 rotations
    
    GridBoard_create(...)
        GridBoard_create(markersX, markersY, markerLength, markerSeparation, dictionary[, firstMarker]) -> retval
        .   * @brief Create a GridBoard object
        .   *
        .   * @param markersX number of markers in X direction
        .   * @param markersY number of markers in Y direction
        .   * @param markerLength marker side length (normally in meters)
        .   * @param markerSeparation separation between two markers (same unit as markerLength)
        .   * @param dictionary dictionary of markers indicating the type of markers
        .   * @param firstMarker id of first marker in dictionary to use on board.
        .   * @return the output GridBoard object
        .   *
        .   * This functions creates a GridBoard object given the number of markers in each direction and
        .   * the marker size and marker separation.
    
    calibrateCameraAruco(...)
        calibrateCameraAruco(corners, ids, counter, board, imageSize, cameraMatrix, distCoeffs[, rvecs[, tvecs[, flags[, criteria]]]]) -> retval, cameraMatrix, distCoeffs, rvecs, tvecs
        .   @brief It's the same function as #calibrateCameraAruco but without calibration error estimation.
    
    calibrateCameraArucoExtended(...)
        calibrateCameraArucoExtended(corners, ids, counter, board, imageSize, cameraMatrix, distCoeffs[, rvecs[, tvecs[, stdDeviationsIntrinsics[, stdDeviationsExtrinsics[, perViewErrors[, flags[, criteria]]]]]]]) -> retval, cameraMatrix, distCoeffs, rvecs, tvecs, stdDeviationsIntrinsics, stdDeviationsExtrinsics, perViewErrors
        .   * @brief Calibrate a camera using aruco markers
        .   *
        .   * @param corners vector of detected marker corners in all frames.
        .   * The corners should have the same format returned by detectMarkers (see #detectMarkers).
        .   * @param ids list of identifiers for each marker in corners
        .   * @param counter number of markers in each frame so that corners and ids can be split
        .   * @param board Marker Board layout
        .   * @param imageSize Size of the image used only to initialize the intrinsic camera matrix.
        .   * @param cameraMatrix Output 3x3 floating-point camera matrix
        .   * \f$A = \vecthreethree{f_x}{0}{c_x}{0}{f_y}{c_y}{0}{0}{1}\f$ . If CV\_CALIB\_USE\_INTRINSIC\_GUESS
        .   * and/or CV_CALIB_FIX_ASPECT_RATIO are specified, some or all of fx, fy, cx, cy must be
        .   * initialized before calling the function.
        .   * @param distCoeffs Output vector of distortion coefficients
        .   * \f$(k_1, k_2, p_1, p_2[, k_3[, k_4, k_5, k_6],[s_1, s_2, s_3, s_4]])\f$ of 4, 5, 8 or 12 elements
        .   * @param rvecs Output vector of rotation vectors (see Rodrigues ) estimated for each board view
        .   * (e.g. std::vector<cv::Mat>>). That is, each k-th rotation vector together with the corresponding
        .   * k-th translation vector (see the next output parameter description) brings the board pattern
        .   * from the model coordinate space (in which object points are specified) to the world coordinate
        .   * space, that is, a real position of the board pattern in the k-th pattern view (k=0.. *M* -1).
        .   * @param tvecs Output vector of translation vectors estimated for each pattern view.
        .   * @param stdDeviationsIntrinsics Output vector of standard deviations estimated for intrinsic parameters.
        .   * Order of deviations values:
        .   * \f$(f_x, f_y, c_x, c_y, k_1, k_2, p_1, p_2, k_3, k_4, k_5, k_6 , s_1, s_2, s_3,
        .   * s_4, \tau_x, \tau_y)\f$ If one of parameters is not estimated, it's deviation is equals to zero.
        .   * @param stdDeviationsExtrinsics Output vector of standard deviations estimated for extrinsic parameters.
        .   * Order of deviations values: \f$(R_1, T_1, \dotsc , R_M, T_M)\f$ where M is number of pattern views,
        .   * \f$R_i, T_i\f$ are concatenated 1x3 vectors.
        .   * @param perViewErrors Output vector of average re-projection errors estimated for each pattern view.
        .   * @param flags flags Different flags  for the calibration process (see #calibrateCamera for details).
        .   * @param criteria Termination criteria for the iterative optimization algorithm.
        .   *
        .   * This function calibrates a camera using an Aruco Board. The function receives a list of
        .   * detected markers from several views of the Board. The process is similar to the chessboard
        .   * calibration in calibrateCamera(). The function returns the final re-projection error.
    
    calibrateCameraCharuco(...)
        calibrateCameraCharuco(charucoCorners, charucoIds, board, imageSize, cameraMatrix, distCoeffs[, rvecs[, tvecs[, flags[, criteria]]]]) -> retval, cameraMatrix, distCoeffs, rvecs, tvecs
        .   @brief It's the same function as #calibrateCameraCharuco but without calibration error estimation.
    
    calibrateCameraCharucoExtended(...)
        calibrateCameraCharucoExtended(charucoCorners, charucoIds, board, imageSize, cameraMatrix, distCoeffs[, rvecs[, tvecs[, stdDeviationsIntrinsics[, stdDeviationsExtrinsics[, perViewErrors[, flags[, criteria]]]]]]]) -> retval, cameraMatrix, distCoeffs, rvecs, tvecs, stdDeviationsIntrinsics, stdDeviationsExtrinsics, perViewErrors
        .   * @brief Calibrate a camera using Charuco corners
        .   *
        .   * @param charucoCorners vector of detected charuco corners per frame
        .   * @param charucoIds list of identifiers for each corner in charucoCorners per frame
        .   * @param board Marker Board layout
        .   * @param imageSize input image size
        .   * @param cameraMatrix Output 3x3 floating-point camera matrix
        .   * \f$A = \vecthreethree{f_x}{0}{c_x}{0}{f_y}{c_y}{0}{0}{1}\f$ . If CV\_CALIB\_USE\_INTRINSIC\_GUESS
        .   * and/or CV_CALIB_FIX_ASPECT_RATIO are specified, some or all of fx, fy, cx, cy must be
        .   * initialized before calling the function.
        .   * @param distCoeffs Output vector of distortion coefficients
        .   * \f$(k_1, k_2, p_1, p_2[, k_3[, k_4, k_5, k_6],[s_1, s_2, s_3, s_4]])\f$ of 4, 5, 8 or 12 elements
        .   * @param rvecs Output vector of rotation vectors (see Rodrigues ) estimated for each board view
        .   * (e.g. std::vector<cv::Mat>>). That is, each k-th rotation vector together with the corresponding
        .   * k-th translation vector (see the next output parameter description) brings the board pattern
        .   * from the model coordinate space (in which object points are specified) to the world coordinate
        .   * space, that is, a real position of the board pattern in the k-th pattern view (k=0.. *M* -1).
        .   * @param tvecs Output vector of translation vectors estimated for each pattern view.
        .   * @param stdDeviationsIntrinsics Output vector of standard deviations estimated for intrinsic parameters.
        .   * Order of deviations values:
        .   * \f$(f_x, f_y, c_x, c_y, k_1, k_2, p_1, p_2, k_3, k_4, k_5, k_6 , s_1, s_2, s_3,
        .   * s_4, \tau_x, \tau_y)\f$ If one of parameters is not estimated, it's deviation is equals to zero.
        .   * @param stdDeviationsExtrinsics Output vector of standard deviations estimated for extrinsic parameters.
        .   * Order of deviations values: \f$(R_1, T_1, \dotsc , R_M, T_M)\f$ where M is number of pattern views,
        .   * \f$R_i, T_i\f$ are concatenated 1x3 vectors.
        .   * @param perViewErrors Output vector of average re-projection errors estimated for each pattern view.
        .   * @param flags flags Different flags  for the calibration process (see #calibrateCamera for details).
        .   * @param criteria Termination criteria for the iterative optimization algorithm.
        .   *
        .   * This function calibrates a camera using a set of corners of a  Charuco Board. The function
        .   * receives a list of detected corners and its identifiers from several views of the Board.
        .   * The function returns the final re-projection error.
    
    custom_dictionary(...)
        custom_dictionary(nMarkers, markerSize[, randomSeed]) -> retval
        .   * @see generateCustomDictionary
    
    custom_dictionary_from(...)
        custom_dictionary_from(nMarkers, markerSize, baseDictionary[, randomSeed]) -> retval
        .   * @brief Generates a new customizable marker dictionary
        .   *
        .   * @param nMarkers number of markers in the dictionary
        .   * @param markerSize number of bits per dimension of each markers
        .   * @param baseDictionary Include the markers in this dictionary at the beginning (optional)
        .   * @param randomSeed a user supplied seed for theRNG()
        .   *
        .   * This function creates a new dictionary composed by nMarkers markers and each markers composed
        .   * by markerSize x markerSize bits. If baseDictionary is provided, its markers are directly
        .   * included and the rest are generated based on them. If the size of baseDictionary is higher
        .   * than nMarkers, only the first nMarkers in baseDictionary are taken and no new marker is added.
    
    detectCharucoDiamond(...)
        detectCharucoDiamond(image, markerCorners, markerIds, squareMarkerLengthRate[, diamondCorners[, diamondIds[, cameraMatrix[, distCoeffs]]]]) -> diamondCorners, diamondIds
        .   * @brief Detect ChArUco Diamond markers
        .   *
        .   * @param image input image necessary for corner subpixel.
        .   * @param markerCorners list of detected marker corners from detectMarkers function.
        .   * @param markerIds list of marker ids in markerCorners.
        .   * @param squareMarkerLengthRate rate between square and marker length:
        .   * squareMarkerLengthRate = squareLength/markerLength. The real units are not necessary.
        .   * @param diamondCorners output list of detected diamond corners (4 corners per diamond). The order
        .   * is the same than in marker corners: top left, top right, bottom right and bottom left. Similar
        .   * format than the corners returned by detectMarkers (e.g std::vector<std::vector<cv::Point2f> > ).
        .   * @param diamondIds ids of the diamonds in diamondCorners. The id of each diamond is in fact of
        .   * type Vec4i, so each diamond has 4 ids, which are the ids of the aruco markers composing the
        .   * diamond.
        .   * @param cameraMatrix Optional camera calibration matrix.
        .   * @param distCoeffs Optional camera distortion coefficients.
        .   *
        .   * This function detects Diamond markers from the previous detected ArUco markers. The diamonds
        .   * are returned in the diamondCorners and diamondIds parameters. If camera calibration parameters
        .   * are provided, the diamond search is based on reprojection. If not, diamond search is based on
        .   * homography. Homography is faster than reprojection but can slightly reduce the detection rate.
    
    detectMarkers(...)
        detectMarkers(image, dictionary[, corners[, ids[, parameters[, rejectedImgPoints[, cameraMatrix[, distCoeff]]]]]]) -> corners, ids, rejectedImgPoints
        .   * @brief Basic marker detection
        .   *
        .   * @param image input image
        .   * @param dictionary indicates the type of markers that will be searched
        .   * @param corners vector of detected marker corners. For each marker, its four corners
        .   * are provided, (e.g std::vector<std::vector<cv::Point2f> > ). For N detected markers,
        .   * the dimensions of this array is Nx4. The order of the corners is clockwise.
        .   * @param ids vector of identifiers of the detected markers. The identifier is of type int
        .   * (e.g. std::vector<int>). For N detected markers, the size of ids is also N.
        .   * The identifiers have the same order than the markers in the imgPoints array.
        .   * @param parameters marker detection parameters
        .   * @param rejectedImgPoints contains the imgPoints of those squares whose inner code has not a
        .   * correct codification. Useful for debugging purposes.
        .   * @param cameraMatrix optional input 3x3 floating-point camera matrix
        .   * \f$A = \vecthreethree{f_x}{0}{c_x}{0}{f_y}{c_y}{0}{0}{1}\f$
        .   * @param distCoeff optional vector of distortion coefficients
        .   * \f$(k_1, k_2, p_1, p_2[, k_3[, k_4, k_5, k_6],[s_1, s_2, s_3, s_4]])\f$ of 4, 5, 8 or 12 elements
        .   *
        .   * Performs marker detection in the input image. Only markers included in the specific dictionary
        .   * are searched. For each detected marker, it returns the 2D position of its corner in the image
        .   * and its corresponding identifier.
        .   * Note that this function does not perform pose estimation.
        .   * @sa estimatePoseSingleMarkers,  estimatePoseBoard
        .   *
    
    drawAxis(...)
        drawAxis(image, cameraMatrix, distCoeffs, rvec, tvec, length) -> image
        .   * @brief Draw coordinate system axis from pose estimation
        .   *
        .   * @param image input/output image. It must have 1 or 3 channels. The number of channels is not
        .   * altered.
        .   * @param cameraMatrix input 3x3 floating-point camera matrix
        .   * \f$A = \vecthreethree{f_x}{0}{c_x}{0}{f_y}{c_y}{0}{0}{1}\f$
        .   * @param distCoeffs vector of distortion coefficients
        .   * \f$(k_1, k_2, p_1, p_2[, k_3[, k_4, k_5, k_6],[s_1, s_2, s_3, s_4]])\f$ of 4, 5, 8 or 12 elements
        .   * @param rvec rotation vector of the coordinate system that will be drawn. (@sa Rodrigues).
        .   * @param tvec translation vector of the coordinate system that will be drawn.
        .   * @param length length of the painted axis in the same unit than tvec (usually in meters)
        .   *
        .   * Given the pose estimation of a marker or board, this function draws the axis of the world
        .   * coordinate system, i.e. the system centered on the marker/board. Useful for debugging purposes.
    
    drawDetectedCornersCharuco(...)
        drawDetectedCornersCharuco(image, charucoCorners[, charucoIds[, cornerColor]]) -> image
        .   * @brief Draws a set of Charuco corners
        .   * @param image input/output image. It must have 1 or 3 channels. The number of channels is not
        .   * altered.
        .   * @param charucoCorners vector of detected charuco corners
        .   * @param charucoIds list of identifiers for each corner in charucoCorners
        .   * @param cornerColor color of the square surrounding each corner
        .   *
        .   * This function draws a set of detected Charuco corners. If identifiers vector is provided, it also
        .   * draws the id of each corner.
    
    drawDetectedDiamonds(...)
        drawDetectedDiamonds(image, diamondCorners[, diamondIds[, borderColor]]) -> image
        .   * @brief Draw a set of detected ChArUco Diamond markers
        .   *
        .   * @param image input/output image. It must have 1 or 3 channels. The number of channels is not
        .   * altered.
        .   * @param diamondCorners positions of diamond corners in the same format returned by
        .   * detectCharucoDiamond(). (e.g std::vector<std::vector<cv::Point2f> > ). For N detected markers,
        .   * the dimensions of this array should be Nx4. The order of the corners should be clockwise.
        .   * @param diamondIds vector of identifiers for diamonds in diamondCorners, in the same format
        .   * returned by detectCharucoDiamond() (e.g. std::vector<Vec4i>).
        .   * Optional, if not provided, ids are not painted.
        .   * @param borderColor color of marker borders. Rest of colors (text color and first corner color)
        .   * are calculated based on this one.
        .   *
        .   * Given an array of detected diamonds, this functions draws them in the image. The marker borders
        .   * are painted and the markers identifiers if provided.
        .   * Useful for debugging purposes.
    
    drawDetectedMarkers(...)
        drawDetectedMarkers(image, corners[, ids[, borderColor]]) -> image
        .   * @brief Draw detected markers in image
        .   *
        .   * @param image input/output image. It must have 1 or 3 channels. The number of channels is not
        .   * altered.
        .   * @param corners positions of marker corners on input image.
        .   * (e.g std::vector<std::vector<cv::Point2f> > ). For N detected markers, the dimensions of
        .   * this array should be Nx4. The order of the corners should be clockwise.
        .   * @param ids vector of identifiers for markers in markersCorners .
        .   * Optional, if not provided, ids are not painted.
        .   * @param borderColor color of marker borders. Rest of colors (text color and first corner color)
        .   * are calculated based on this one to improve visualization.
        .   *
        .   * Given an array of detected marker corners and its corresponding ids, this functions draws
        .   * the markers in the image. The marker borders are painted and the markers identifiers if provided.
        .   * Useful for debugging purposes.
    
    drawMarker(...)
        drawMarker(dictionary, id, sidePixels[, img[, borderBits]]) -> img
        .   * @brief Draw a canonical marker image
        .   *
        .   * @param dictionary dictionary of markers indicating the type of markers
        .   * @param id identifier of the marker that will be returned. It has to be a valid id
        .   * in the specified dictionary.
        .   * @param sidePixels size of the image in pixels
        .   * @param img output image with the marker
        .   * @param borderBits width of the marker border.
        .   *
        .   * This function returns a marker image in its canonical form (i.e. ready to be printed)
    
    drawPlanarBoard(...)
        drawPlanarBoard(board, outSize[, img[, marginSize[, borderBits]]]) -> img
        .   * @brief Draw a planar board
        .   * @sa _drawPlanarBoardImpl
        .   *
        .   * @param board layout of the board that will be drawn. The board should be planar,
        .   * z coordinate is ignored
        .   * @param outSize size of the output image in pixels.
        .   * @param img output image with the board. The size of this image will be outSize
        .   * and the board will be on the center, keeping the board proportions.
        .   * @param marginSize minimum margins (in pixels) of the board in the output image
        .   * @param borderBits width of the marker borders.
        .   *
        .   * This function return the image of a planar board, ready to be printed. It assumes
        .   * the Board layout specified is planar by ignoring the z coordinates of the object points.
    
    estimatePoseBoard(...)
        estimatePoseBoard(corners, ids, board, cameraMatrix, distCoeffs[, rvec[, tvec[, useExtrinsicGuess]]]) -> retval, rvec, tvec
        .   * @brief Pose estimation for a board of markers
        .   *
        .   * @param corners vector of already detected markers corners. For each marker, its four corners
        .   * are provided, (e.g std::vector<std::vector<cv::Point2f> > ). For N detected markers, the
        .   * dimensions of this array should be Nx4. The order of the corners should be clockwise.
        .   * @param ids list of identifiers for each marker in corners
        .   * @param board layout of markers in the board. The layout is composed by the marker identifiers
        .   * and the positions of each marker corner in the board reference system.
        .   * @param cameraMatrix input 3x3 floating-point camera matrix
        .   * \f$A = \vecthreethree{f_x}{0}{c_x}{0}{f_y}{c_y}{0}{0}{1}\f$
        .   * @param distCoeffs vector of distortion coefficients
        .   * \f$(k_1, k_2, p_1, p_2[, k_3[, k_4, k_5, k_6],[s_1, s_2, s_3, s_4]])\f$ of 4, 5, 8 or 12 elements
        .   * @param rvec Output vector (e.g. cv::Mat) corresponding to the rotation vector of the board
        .   * (see cv::Rodrigues). Used as initial guess if not empty.
        .   * @param tvec Output vector (e.g. cv::Mat) corresponding to the translation vector of the board.
        .   * @param useExtrinsicGuess defines whether initial guess for \b rvec and \b tvec will be used or not.
        .   * Used as initial guess if not empty.
        .   *
        .   * This function receives the detected markers and returns the pose of a marker board composed
        .   * by those markers.
        .   * A Board of marker has a single world coordinate system which is defined by the board layout.
        .   * The returned transformation is the one that transforms points from the board coordinate system
        .   * to the camera coordinate system.
        .   * Input markers that are not included in the board layout are ignored.
        .   * The function returns the number of markers from the input employed for the board pose estimation.
        .   * Note that returning a 0 means the pose has not been estimated.
    
    estimatePoseCharucoBoard(...)
        estimatePoseCharucoBoard(charucoCorners, charucoIds, board, cameraMatrix, distCoeffs[, rvec[, tvec[, useExtrinsicGuess]]]) -> retval, rvec, tvec
        .   * @brief Pose estimation for a ChArUco board given some of their corners
        .   * @param charucoCorners vector of detected charuco corners
        .   * @param charucoIds list of identifiers for each corner in charucoCorners
        .   * @param board layout of ChArUco board.
        .   * @param cameraMatrix input 3x3 floating-point camera matrix
        .   * \f$A = \vecthreethree{f_x}{0}{c_x}{0}{f_y}{c_y}{0}{0}{1}\f$
        .   * @param distCoeffs vector of distortion coefficients
        .   * \f$(k_1, k_2, p_1, p_2[, k_3[, k_4, k_5, k_6],[s_1, s_2, s_3, s_4]])\f$ of 4, 5, 8 or 12 elements
        .   * @param rvec Output vector (e.g. cv::Mat) corresponding to the rotation vector of the board
        .   * (see cv::Rodrigues).
        .   * @param tvec Output vector (e.g. cv::Mat) corresponding to the translation vector of the board.
        .   * @param useExtrinsicGuess defines whether initial guess for \b rvec and \b tvec will be used or not.
        .   *
        .   * This function estimates a Charuco board pose from some detected corners.
        .   * The function checks if the input corners are enough and valid to perform pose estimation.
        .   * If pose estimation is valid, returns true, else returns false.
    
    estimatePoseSingleMarkers(...)
        estimatePoseSingleMarkers(corners, markerLength, cameraMatrix, distCoeffs[, rvecs[, tvecs[, _objPoints]]]) -> rvecs, tvecs, _objPoints
        .   * @brief Pose estimation for single markers
        .   *
        .   * @param corners vector of already detected markers corners. For each marker, its four corners
        .   * are provided, (e.g std::vector<std::vector<cv::Point2f> > ). For N detected markers,
        .   * the dimensions of this array should be Nx4. The order of the corners should be clockwise.
        .   * @sa detectMarkers
        .   * @param markerLength the length of the markers' side. The returning translation vectors will
        .   * be in the same unit. Normally, unit is meters.
        .   * @param cameraMatrix input 3x3 floating-point camera matrix
        .   * \f$A = \vecthreethree{f_x}{0}{c_x}{0}{f_y}{c_y}{0}{0}{1}\f$
        .   * @param distCoeffs vector of distortion coefficients
        .   * \f$(k_1, k_2, p_1, p_2[, k_3[, k_4, k_5, k_6],[s_1, s_2, s_3, s_4]])\f$ of 4, 5, 8 or 12 elements
        .   * @param rvecs array of output rotation vectors (@sa Rodrigues) (e.g. std::vector<cv::Vec3d>).
        .   * Each element in rvecs corresponds to the specific marker in imgPoints.
        .   * @param tvecs array of output translation vectors (e.g. std::vector<cv::Vec3d>).
        .   * Each element in tvecs corresponds to the specific marker in imgPoints.
        .   * @param _objPoints array of object points of all the marker corners
        .   *
        .   * This function receives the detected markers and returns their pose estimation respect to
        .   * the camera individually. So for each marker, one rotation and translation vector is returned.
        .   * The returned transformation is the one that transforms points from each marker coordinate system
        .   * to the camera coordinate system.
        .   * The marker corrdinate system is centered on the middle of the marker, with the Z axis
        .   * perpendicular to the marker plane.
        .   * The coordinates of the four corners of the marker in its own coordinate system are:
        .   * (-markerLength/2, markerLength/2, 0), (markerLength/2, markerLength/2, 0),
        .   * (markerLength/2, -markerLength/2, 0), (-markerLength/2, -markerLength/2, 0)
    
    getBoardObjectAndImagePoints(...)
        getBoardObjectAndImagePoints(board, detectedCorners, detectedIds[, objPoints[, imgPoints]]) -> objPoints, imgPoints
        .   * @brief Given a board configuration and a set of detected markers, returns the corresponding
        .   * image points and object points to call solvePnP
        .   *
        .   * @param board Marker board layout.
        .   * @param detectedCorners List of detected marker corners of the board.
        .   * @param detectedIds List of identifiers for each marker.
        .   * @param objPoints Vector of vectors of board marker points in the board coordinate space.
        .   * @param imgPoints Vector of vectors of the projections of board marker corner points.
    
    getPredefinedDictionary(...)
        getPredefinedDictionary(dict) -> retval
        .   * @brief Returns one of the predefined dictionaries referenced by DICT_*.
    
    interpolateCornersCharuco(...)
        interpolateCornersCharuco(markerCorners, markerIds, image, board[, charucoCorners[, charucoIds[, cameraMatrix[, distCoeffs[, minMarkers]]]]]) -> retval, charucoCorners, charucoIds
        .   * @brief Interpolate position of ChArUco board corners
        .   * @param markerCorners vector of already detected markers corners. For each marker, its four
        .   * corners are provided, (e.g std::vector<std::vector<cv::Point2f> > ). For N detected markers, the
        .   * dimensions of this array should be Nx4. The order of the corners should be clockwise.
        .   * @param markerIds list of identifiers for each marker in corners
        .   * @param image input image necesary for corner refinement. Note that markers are not detected and
        .   * should be sent in corners and ids parameters.
        .   * @param board layout of ChArUco board.
        .   * @param charucoCorners interpolated chessboard corners
        .   * @param charucoIds interpolated chessboard corners identifiers
        .   * @param cameraMatrix optional 3x3 floating-point camera matrix
        .   * \f$A = \vecthreethree{f_x}{0}{c_x}{0}{f_y}{c_y}{0}{0}{1}\f$
        .   * @param distCoeffs optional vector of distortion coefficients
        .   * \f$(k_1, k_2, p_1, p_2[, k_3[, k_4, k_5, k_6],[s_1, s_2, s_3, s_4]])\f$ of 4, 5, 8 or 12 elements
        .   * @param minMarkers number of adjacent markers that must be detected to return a charuco corner
        .   *
        .   * This function receives the detected markers and returns the 2D position of the chessboard corners
        .   * from a ChArUco board using the detected Aruco markers. If camera parameters are provided,
        .   * the process is based in an approximated pose estimation, else it is based on local homography.
        .   * Only visible corners are returned. For each corner, its corresponding identifier is
        .   * also returned in charucoIds.
        .   * The function returns the number of interpolated corners.
    
    refineDetectedMarkers(...)
        refineDetectedMarkers(image, board, detectedCorners, detectedIds, rejectedCorners[, cameraMatrix[, distCoeffs[, minRepDistance[, errorCorrectionRate[, checkAllOrders[, recoveredIdxs[, parameters]]]]]]]) -> detectedCorners, detectedIds, rejectedCorners, recoveredIdxs
        .   * @brief Refind not detected markers based on the already detected and the board layout
        .   *
        .   * @param image input image
        .   * @param board layout of markers in the board.
        .   * @param detectedCorners vector of already detected marker corners.
        .   * @param detectedIds vector of already detected marker identifiers.
        .   * @param rejectedCorners vector of rejected candidates during the marker detection process.
        .   * @param cameraMatrix optional input 3x3 floating-point camera matrix
        .   * \f$A = \vecthreethree{f_x}{0}{c_x}{0}{f_y}{c_y}{0}{0}{1}\f$
        .   * @param distCoeffs optional vector of distortion coefficients
        .   * \f$(k_1, k_2, p_1, p_2[, k_3[, k_4, k_5, k_6],[s_1, s_2, s_3, s_4]])\f$ of 4, 5, 8 or 12 elements
        .   * @param minRepDistance minimum distance between the corners of the rejected candidate and the
        .   * reprojected marker in order to consider it as a correspondence.
        .   * @param errorCorrectionRate rate of allowed erroneous bits respect to the error correction
        .   * capability of the used dictionary. -1 ignores the error correction step.
        .   * @param checkAllOrders Consider the four posible corner orders in the rejectedCorners array.
        .   * If it set to false, only the provided corner order is considered (default true).
        .   * @param recoveredIdxs Optional array to returns the indexes of the recovered candidates in the
        .   * original rejectedCorners array.
        .   * @param parameters marker detection parameters
        .   *
        .   * This function tries to find markers that were not detected in the basic detecMarkers function.
        .   * First, based on the current detected marker and the board layout, the function interpolates
        .   * the position of the missing markers. Then it tries to find correspondence between the reprojected
        .   * markers and the rejected candidates based on the minRepDistance and errorCorrectionRate
        .   * parameters.
        .   * If camera parameters and distortion coefficients are provided, missing markers are reprojected
        .   * using projectPoint function. If not, missing marker projections are interpolated using global
        .   * homography, and all the marker corners in the board must have the same Z coordinate.

DATA
    CORNER_REFINE_APRILTAG = 3
    CORNER_REFINE_CONTOUR = 2
    CORNER_REFINE_NONE = 0
    CORNER_REFINE_SUBPIX = 1
    DICT_4X4_100 = 1
    DICT_4X4_1000 = 3
    DICT_4X4_250 = 2
    DICT_4X4_50 = 0
    DICT_5X5_100 = 5
    DICT_5X5_1000 = 7
    DICT_5X5_250 = 6
    DICT_5X5_50 = 4
    DICT_6X6_100 = 9
    DICT_6X6_1000 = 11
    DICT_6X6_250 = 10
    DICT_6X6_50 = 8
    DICT_7X7_100 = 13
    DICT_7X7_1000 = 15
    DICT_7X7_250 = 14
    DICT_7X7_50 = 12
    DICT_APRILTAG_16H5 = 17
    DICT_APRILTAG_16h5 = 17
    DICT_APRILTAG_25H9 = 18
    DICT_APRILTAG_25h9 = 18
    DICT_APRILTAG_36H10 = 19
    DICT_APRILTAG_36H11 = 20
    DICT_APRILTAG_36h10 = 19
    DICT_APRILTAG_36h11 = 20
    DICT_ARUCO_ORIGINAL = 16

FILE
    (built-in)


